You've done this three times now as a
head coach. How are you different today
than you were three years ago walking in
as a rookie? And where do you think you
are kind of in that spectrum of learning
this job?
>> I guess the first thing I could say is
just learning who we are as a as an
organization, learning our players,
learning our staff members, and and
where we're headed, you know, culturally
and philosophically.
we Dan, myself and uh and Brent just
connecting with each other and
understanding what we want what we want
out of this process, you know, what we
want out of our own team and where we're
headed. So having that makes all the
difference. Of course, as you can
imagine, coming in here the first time
and saying, "Okay, this is what I would
like to be. You know, we're closer to
that now." And while we're every year we
have to restart and say, "Okay, we got
to recreate what we believe in again
with this new group. Even some of the
names are the same. they will all be
different in different times in their
lives. Uh different personal dynamics
happening, contract, different
situations like that. So all those
things have a have a way of shifting
people's perspectives and it's our job
to rec reconnect with all those people
so we can move forward.
>> Do you anticipate
>> both?
>> What's that?
>> Are you expecting to miss even the bulk
of the season? I don't know that really.
And uh you know with the patella tendon
injury, you know, there's there's a
there's a timeline for when you're
cleared to work on the field and then
you just have to take it from there. So
we're going to just hit that date first.
Icky's been there every day grinding,
working hard um with our staff to get
the strength, get the range of motion
and all those things back and we'll take
it, you know, as it comes.
>> So you came in first year head coach Dan
Morgan, first year GM. You just talk
about how the trust has grown, you know,
with the benching of Bryce. That was a
hard decision. Everybody expected you to
go to defense and you drafted, you know,
Tedo McMillan that paid off dividend.
Can you just talk about how that
relationship has grown, how you guys are
growing together?
>> Just our commitment to creating
relationship. Um, the two of us and I
have to any of these conversations I
have to include Brent because this is a
group where from a day-to-day
standpoint, you know, we talk a lot.
We're on the phone together. We're
sitting in an office. We're hashing
things out talking about where we're
heading. talking about right now, you
know, and and uh just making sure that
we're connected in that level allows us
to make decisions quicker because we
understand what we're after and the
types of players that we're looking for,
who our current roster is and what their
next steps are. Uh putting a staff
together, all those things. Um it just
takes time to kind of create that
chemistry and and we're committed to it.
We're committed to each other and and
supporting each other and making sure we
can have open, honest conversation. And
we don't always agree, but at the at the
end of the day, hopefully we're all
heard.
>> How much is how much is
Beville's knowledge of like
mid zone and outside zone temp
and everything.
>> Yeah, they're a wide zone system uh
primarily and and there's a lot of
things that you know that I admire from
the outside looking in things that I
would like to see if they can affect our
offense in a positive way. But we have
our own approach and the good part is
Daryl knows that approach too. So, it's
a really unique situation where I've
been talking with Brad, with our staff
about the evolution of some of our
concepts in the pass game, in the run
game that have happened over the years.
So, it's really unique to have Daryl
come back now with fresh perspective and
the memory to know like where it all
started, how we evolved these things
because if we can understand where we've
been to where we're at, then hopefully
we can push forward to where we're
going. Dave, do you have any Luke
Keequley stories from your days in
Seattle? Either game planning,
preparing, or maybe some feedback
because he was famous for knowing what
plays you guys were trying to run, the
opponents were trying to run.
>> I just remember him being so restless
out there and it's just like never
stopped moving, waving his arms like
crazy, bringing safeties down in
rotation, sideline to sideline, making
plays, just a beautiful player. And in
Seattle, you know, our our whole thing
was like defense, run game, toughness,
all that. And it just felt like whenever
we played the Panthers, especially with
Luke in the middle, it was always kind
of like we were facing a brother and and
the style of play in the in the way that
they went about their business. And Luke
was certainly right in the center of
that.
>> You mentioned um giving up play calling
kind of frees you up in other areas of
the game. Were you looking at Tate from
this previous season? And was there a
moment where you said, "Okay, if I
wasn't to to the next play, maybe I
would have been able to challenge
something.
>> There were there were quite a few
moments that way. Um I think there was
looking for some of the interactions to
be more um more constructive and for
myself to be available uh for the
officials to have conversations that
way. Uh making game management
decisions, all those things which you
guys can imagine is is a challenge to
call plays and do those things. I
understood the challenge of it. I was
accepting of that challenge. But it goes
beyond that. It's also being able to
affect and impact your players really
live as guys come on and off the field
to be able to connect with them to see
something fundamentally I know can help
this player. Let's not wait until Monday
when I watch the film to be able to help
somebody, you know, and and or talk to a
coach and say, "Hey, this is happening.
Can I affect our whole team in a more
positive way?" And this is an
opportunity for me to do that.
>> And just as a followup, I know Peter is
one of your mentors. Did you have
anybody conversations with any Before
you made this decision,
>> this was something I had to keep in
house and uh speak with Dan about, rant
about Mr. Ter. We were all on the same
page. They understood what I was trying
to get done and and how we were trying
to do that and um so I did that with all
of us being connected. So we made made
sure that I had the full support of the
group um to make this decision.
>> How much was it putting your ego aside?
I know a lot of guys you admire, they
want to call the plays and there's a got
to be a level of ego in wanting to do
that. So how much was that involved? Um,
it it was a big part of it and uh just
thinking about wanting to make sure I'm
doing the right thing for the team first
and foremost. And that's that's always
where I'm going to default with any of
the big decisions that happen for the
Panthers football team that I'm in
charge of. It's going to be about
putting our players in the best position
to be successful. And as I watch that, I
see an opportunity for two things to
grow. For Brad to be able to affect the
offense in a positive way, and for
myself to be able to affect the whole
thing um in that way. But it certainly
was something that I looked at and look
around at the coaches that are able to
get this done. It gives me such a huge
level of respect for the guys that have
been successful doing this this model of
being the play caller on offense or
defense and also being the head coach
and interacting with different things
that come across your desk on a daily
basis, you know, and um and what a great
opportunity and challenge it's been to
be able to see that and to and to really
respect the guys that do it at a high
level. Kind of on that note though, do
you think you'll have to caution
yourself during games from like going
over there and being like, "Hey, what
about this? What about that?" Or or will
you give yourself that freedom if
something really just stands out to you?
>> Uh, we'll see.
>> Dan has been pretty open about wanting
to bring in another quarterback. What
are you guys looking for in that in that
Q?
>> Yeah, just looking for someone to
compete in our room um to challenge our
roster. First and foremost, talking
about our evaluation process starts with
our current players. How do we help all
of our guys develop? That's our first
commitment. How do we help them take the
next step? So, we're looking at all that
film. We'll connect them when they get
back. Then, it's looking at our players
who returning from injury. How do we get
them back going? How are they going to
impact our team? Um, and then it's also
about looking at the guys that we've had
who are free agents. Who are the guys
that can continue to help us or or or
create, you know, competition in their
rooms? Then we go to this process in
free agency and see who we can add. And
so as we look at the quarterback room um
with some amazing men in there, is there
somebody that can come in and challenge
and that that uh room?
>> The Buffalo game, uh Andy, you kind of
got a little overwhelmed by the rush.
Would you be looking for someone maybe a
little more mobile for that position?
>> We we'll consider all those
possibilities.
>> What do you feel like leave Bryce with
that you feel like he's got to do this
off season to take his game and the
offense? Yeah, just continue to pour
into our system, our concepts, the
ownership of it. I love the strides
we've taken in terms of the operation,
how he gets us up there, makes great
calls, fixes our protection problems,
you know, finding solutions in areas
where we've talked about to take
advantage of coverages, take advantage
of of uh of different fronts, you know,
for run plays and uh just wanting Bryce
to continue to grow in the ownership of
those things because there are more
opportunities for for Bryce to affect
the game at the line of scrimmage and I
want to continue to build off of that.
Any examples in games this year you was
I wish you'd have done this.
>> No, but I got good examples of you know
in the playoff game Bryce getting you
know getting in a 3x1 formation he saw a
particular coverage and got us to an
explosive play to Jaylen Coker down the
field and it was it was the study it was
the understanding it was getting out of
the huddle in a timely fashion and being
able to seize a moment. I want more
moments like that for Bryce and I
believe that's where we're headed.
>> Do you have an example? I know you said
there were a lot of them, but maybe one
you could point to where you felt like,
boy, if I hadn't been with the offense
between series, I would have challenged
that or I would have done this or talked
to a Jerro about this.
>> I have a lot. Um, I want to I want to
stay away from some of those because
they may be a little bit sensitive uh in
in some areas, but it's not just about
the about specific situations for uh
game management or penalty usage or
different things like that. It's also
just affecting players and when I see
when I see a player maybe he may not
realize that he's carrying the ball
loosely. That's something I can go
directly over and address as he's coming
off the field where I don't have to go
to the next play. I want to be able to
affect the culture and the um the
general way we play our play style, you
know, and the things that we always
point back to. I want to be able to make
sure that that's happening on a play in
and playout basis.
>> It seems like this is the last one. off
season so far has been reflective for
you. Did you have an opportunity to kind
of bask in the fact that in your second
year the Panthers did win the NFC South?
>> It's exciting. The growth is exciting.
Uh the the building is excited about
where we're headed. I'm proud of that,
but I also understand how hard it was to
get to that point to be available to win
this the division to make the playoffs.
Um I know the type of work that it takes
and it really starts now. And um so
while I've had a chance to reflect, it's
like we got to go and there's an urgency
about our group, we all understand that
we didn't play good enough in that game
and there was an opportunity to win that
game and we didn't seize that. That's
something that we can take into this
offseason and say here were those
moments. Here's how we improve those
things so that we're ready when those
opportunities come.
>> Oh. Um so I I talked about Bryce being
invol involved in the process. This
wasn't um this wasn't me asking Bryce to
be involved in the decision. This was a
decision made I wanted him to be a part
of on the front end of it instead of
hearing from it secondhand. Those are
those were conversations that he and I
had him informed kind of.
>> Uh it's it's been over the last couple
of weeks we've had a couple of
conversations about that.
>> So it's more so just keeping him
informed.
>> Absolutely. Which I think is really
important.
[music]
Hey, hey, hey.